♪ Pink hands so fine ♪
♪ Gold-branded wine ♪
♪ Spring paints willows green;
palace walls can't confine ♪
♪ East wind unfair ♪
♪ Happy times rare ♪
♪ In my heart, sad thoughts throng ♪
♪ We've severed for years long ♪
♪ Wrong, wrong, wrong ♪
Si Jin
Episode 12
(Matchmaker Wang's Hall)
Zhen,
there's something
I...
I'd like to clarify.
Go ahead.
That day...
Mr. Zhen.
Mr. Yu.
Commandant Yu.
Miss Si.
What are you two doing?
Having tea.
Yes.
I can see that.
What a nice surprise.
Miss Si,
this year's new tea
looks really nice.
I've packed some
for you to bring back.
Thanks, Mrs. Zhen.
Mother, this is
Commandant Yu of Capital Security.
Greetings, Mrs. Zhen.
You really are
a charming young man.
That's very nice of you to say.
You've had tea.
It's boring to sit here and do nothing.
The weather looks nice.
Miss Si, Heng,
let's go on an outing to the suburbs.
I'm sorry
to disappoint you.
Mr. Zhen is needed
at the Capital Security Office.
I see.
No wonder Commandant Yu
came in a rush.
Mother,
I need to go to work.
Sorry, I can't keep you company.
My apologies, Miss Si.
Please excuse me.
Good day.
Come on, Mr. Zhen.
Let's go, Commandant Yu.
Good day, Mrs. Zhen.
That silly boy!
My son only
cares about his work.
You look gorgeous, Pei.
You're getting married, my dear.
Don't you look forward
to seeing me marry Administrator Lin?
You should be happy.
I am happy. I really am.
She'll miss you when you're away.
I made this handkerchief
for your wedding.
Here's some money for you.
The clan has prepared a dowry for me.
Keep the money to yourself.
Once you leave,
your life will be different.
Money can bring you
security.
Don't be as self-willed as before.
If you get hurt,
do let me know.
Once we marry,
I'll be a good wife.
Don't worry about me.
"Cry the fish hawks on sandbars in the river.
A mild-mannered good girl,
fine match for the gentleman.
A ragged fringe is the floating-heart,
left and right we trail it."
How dull and tedious!
I'm tired of studying.
Young Master, Miss Si said
you had to copy this whole book today.
No way. I can't.
What are you doing, Master Qin?
Does studying make you tired?
- Come on.
- Can we hang out?
Let's learn martial arts.
No, I won't go!
I can't!
Come on!
Ji, fetch the basin.
No, no.
I'm up.
Too... too fierce.
That's too much.
Young Master!
Passed out already?
Goodness!
Stop beating that basin.
You're making me deaf.
It's still early.
I can take a nap.
Stop beating it!
Come on!
I quit.
I'm exhausted.
(Morning Drizzle)
Young Master,
before Master Qin left,
he told Miss Si
to have me watch you practice every day.
I can't do it anymore,
or I'll die.
Who is this?
It's only been days.
What happened to you?
What brings you here?
To laugh at me?
Don't give up, Jiang Zhan.
Jiang Si asked me
to teach you self-defense skills
that Master Qin hadn't mentioned.
Good heavens!
Si is insane!
Chuchu,
do me a favor, will you?
Knock me out.
I can't do it anymore.
Shut up and do as I say.
Let's begin today's practice.
Fine.
Alright. Let's do it!
What is it?
I'll do whatever you say.
This is
what we're going to do.
What do you mean?
I know over the past few days,
you've been exhausted.
It takes time to learn
martial arts.
It can't be rushed,
or it'll do more harm than good.
To learn my skills,
you need to recover your energy first.
Miss Lu,
I've never seen anyone
as smart
and kind as you!
Save it.
Eat up.
It's so good to be outside.
I could use some fresh air
after being grounded for days.
It was Jiang Si's fault.
I'll make her pay someday.
Ji, fetch a pot of liquor.
Yes.
- Eat with me.
- Who's that?
No, thanks.
Ms. Xiao,
that's Miss Si's friend,
Lu Chuchu.
Lu Chuchu?
Is that a girl?
Why is she
- dressed like that?
- Try it.
Obviously,
- she's not a decent girl,
- Eat it.
but a humble civilian.
Jiang Si
planted her people
in our mansion
when I was grounded.
Clearly,
she's eager to
replace me as the matriarch.
Mother.
Although you've been freed,
from now on,
watch what you say and do.
Don't make mistakes ever again.
Yes, Mother.
I'll keep that in mind.
Let me do it.
Mother,
when I was sick,
you managed everything at home. Thanks.
I'm glad you know it.
I reflected on myself
in my room in the last few days.
I failed to run the household well,
unlike Si. Look,
she's kept everything in order.
Even Zhan has become better.
I heard he started
practicing martial arts.
They were fooling around.
I noticed a girl
in our mansion
who I had never seen before.
She and Zhan
seemed quite close.
Who was that?
Mrs. Li,
do you know her?
My Lady,
she's Miss Si's friend,
Lu Chuchu.
Her background is unknown.
Refugees have been
sneaking into the city lately.
What if she's one of them?
A refugee?
That's fine
as long as she's honest,
and Zhan likes her.
I agree, Mother.
You're right.
Just now,
we saw her
on the way here.
She looked like a tough girl.
I wonder why a Han like her
was dressed as a Tartar.
My Lady,
a few days ago, I saw her
feeding Young Master Zhan
in the garden.
Actually, they were feeding each other.
She was as if seducing him.
Alright, that's enough.
What nonsense is that?
Don't be mad, Mother.
Please calm down.
If she really is like what Mrs. Li said,
that girl is dishonest.
Zhan's marriage is one thing.
We can't risk
the honor of our clan.
Stop.
Say no more.
I won't allow anyone in our house
to marry a mysterious girl like her!
Yes.
Greetings, Grandmother.
Why did you ask to see me?
Zhan,
what's the relationship between you
and Miss Lu Chuchu?
She's Commandant Yu's friend,
and she's made friends with Si, too.
How... how did she
and Commandant Yu meet?
They've known each other since childhood.
Why are you suddenly
taking an interest in her?
What I'm saying is
if you like her,
you should tell me.
But ask yourself
how well
you know her.
You're familiar
with our family rules.
Mysterious
and dishonest girls like her
will not be accepted by our clan!
Grandmother,
you're biased against her.
First,
she and I
are just friends.
Nothing else is going on between us.
Second, she's
General-in-chief Huaihua's daughter.
How is she mysterious?
What? General-in-chief Huaihua
is her... father?
Correct.
He's well-known and awe-inspiring,
having killed countless enemies
and achieved notable merits.
He's a war hero!
Is...
what you said true?
Of course.
Besides,
she helped those in need
along the way
and spent all her money
on refugees.
How could you call her dishonest?
She spent all her money on refugees?
She has a heart of gold.
She does.
Don't listen to those rumors others said.
Let me pour you some water.
You can relax, My Lady.
Mother.
Mother, Lu Chuchu
is terrible!
You had me tell her
to stay away from Zhan, right?
She was ill-mannered
and extremely mean to me!
Aunt Xiao.
Zhan?
Who did you mean?
Chief,
I get it.
You have feelings for Miss Si.
But what I don't get is
if you like her, why not take action?
Even a scholar like Mr. Zhen
went uphill to gather Lan-tsao
for Miss Si.
If it were me,
I'd be so touched as to marry him.
So what if he got a pot?
I can gather 100 pots!
If he... he thinks he can
be a fighter,
then I can be a scholar.
One pot of plant makes a decent gift.
100 pots are ridiculous.
What is love?
It's intangible and romantic.
It spreads
behind the unspoken words.
Your simple and crude idea
will only ruin the romance
and its misty beauty.
Do you have a better idea?
People used to convey love by letter.
Now,
we can use crabapple flowers.
Chief said
a fighter like him
didn't know how to look after plants.
Leaves
of this pot of crabapple keep falling.
It might be caused
by the soil.
He had me bring this pot to Miss Si to...
If you couldn't tend it,
you'd better stay away from all plants.
Hey, I'm not done yet.
Why is she mad?
Was I being too subtle?
Nah.
Once Miss Si digs,
she'll see it.
That day,
I meant to take the chance
to clear the air with Mr. Zhen
and his mother,
but I couldn't say no to them
and didn't get to make it clear.
It's better to leave it that way.
Miss, I've begun to think
Mr. Zhen is really nice.
As quiet as he seems,
he likes you wholeheartedly.
To gather this pot of Lan-tsao,
he cut his hand and lost blood.
Unlike Mr. Yu who returned
the crabapple from you.
He took an arrow
for you
and almost lost his life.
He helped you out again
on Lady Jiang's birthday.
But...
Aman,
forget about Mr. Yu.
Don't worry.
Mr. Zhen is a wonderful man,
but
he can't make my heart flutter.
I simply
appreciate him as a friend.
That's not love.
If no one
can make my heart flutter,
I'll remain single forever.
Things are going so well now.
I have Zhan, my father,
and you with me.
This is great.
I'm more than content.
Am I right?
(Fragrant Dew)
Are you sure it's Jiang Si's shop?
Yes.
Your Grace,
my wife used to own that shop.
It was a lucrative business.
Jiang Si
must've
tricked my wife
into giving away that shop.
You couldn't even
control a businesswoman you married.
And here you are complaining to me?
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
I am but a scholar.
I'm too kind
to deal with
that deep and scheming woman.
What's wrong with women?
Weren't you born by one?
You're incompetent.
Don't blame it on a woman.
This perfume smells good.
I wonder if it works as well.
Your Grace, are you...?
I'm not you.
Those who annoyed me
will suffer for sure.
(Fragrance Shop)
Look, everyone!
Come and look!
This shop is a trap!
It's run by heartless animals!
We used their balm
and grew rashes all over the face!
Look at my face!
Look, everyone! Look!
Ladies,
why are you making a scene in my shop?
Why?
Look at me, everyone!
Look!
The balm I bought
from this shop
ruined my face.
This shop is a trap.
It's a trap!
How could I live on?
How heartless!
How dare you sell such poison!
Aren't you afraid of karma?
No one will buy their products again!
It's a trap! A trap!
Trash it!
Smash everything!
Trash it! Trash it!
- Smash!
Nobody moves!
Are you hitting her?
Help!
She's hitting us! Help!
She's violent!
Chuchu, let her go.
Jiang Si...
Let her go, Chuchu.
We demand an explanation.
How dare she hit her!
- Yes.
- That's right.
Sorry about this.
Ma'am,
where's the rest
of the balm you used?
May I take a look?
Don't try to destroy the evidence.
We're all watching you.
Yes. Right.
That's right.
Don't worry.
I'll test it right here.
Rou'er, show them
the rest of all our balm.
Pick any jar
from our stock.
I'll test it right in front of you.
Rou'er, bring me the picked ones.
Sure.
You said the balm from our shop
ruined your face.
I'll test it myself here and now.
She used this jar.
Take a look
at these two jars
and smell them.
Take a sniff, everyone.
Their scents are different.
They aren't the same.
They smell differently, right?
Yes, how come?
That's right. She added
Ruyi Grass
to the balm she used.
That's a poisonous plant
that's corrosive to the skin.
What grass? I've never heard of it.
It was your balm
that disfigured my face!
This shop is to blame!
- It's a trap!
- If you insist on
making groundless accusations,
let's go to court.
We aren't afraid of being checked.
Sue me.
I'm not scared!
Your shop is a trap, indeed!
Aman, go to the Capital Security Office.
Ask their officials to come here
to uphold justice.
Yes.
Go ahead and sue me!
You're selling poison!
- You're evil!
- Yes!
You bribed officials.
This shop is a trap!
It's a trap! A trap!
Stop! Come back!
Chuchu.
Let them go.
But they...
You saw everything.
Isn't it clear who's guilty?
They came to make a scene on purpose.
Rou'er, fetch
the new fragrant tablets we made
and give them to the ladies.
Go home
and try them.
See for yourself
the quality of our products.
- Thanks.
- It smells nice.
Thanks.
Thank you, Miss.
So fragrant.
I like its aroma.
Jiang Si,
why did you stop me
from chasing them just now?
I'm afraid
there's more to this matter.
(Haitang Chamber)
Have some tea.
You've been doing the accounts all night.
They smashed away
six months' profits
earlier today.
We had finally had some spare money.
Also, you had paid a lot to run the mansion.
What should we do now?
Even if we sell all the valuables here,
it's still not enough.
How about we borrow some money
from Qiaoniang?
We can't.
I've annoyed Duke An's Mansion.
If others find out
that she helped me,
how can she keep a foothold in their mansion?
I'll figure something out.
(Morning Drizzle)
Er'niu!
Miss.
What are these?
Banknotes!
1,000 taels altogether!
(500 Taels)
Er'niu,
you aren't a dog
but the God of Wealth.
But he took so much money
from whom?
Who else could it be
but Mr. Yu?
Him?
Miss,
could they be forged?
How could he have
so much money?
Forged?
He doesn't
seem too rich.
Yes. He lives in a small house.
Nothing he eats, wears, or uses
seems expensive.
Miss,
looks like I was wrong
about him.
Mr. Yu is the one
who's obsessed with you.
That's not
what you said the other day.
A friend in need is
a friend indeed, right?
Think about it.
A poor man like him
must've used every possible means
to gather 1,000 tales,
and he gave it all to you.
If that's not true love, what else is?
Aman,
did he borrow it from a loan shark?
The compound interest is disastrous!
Er'niu.
Mr. Yu...
Are you taking a walk?
I'm bringing Er'niu back.
I can tell.
Mr. Yu,
(500 Taels)
I can't take your 1,000 taels.
Your shop was smashed.
Aren't you in urgent need of money?
Even so,
I can't take your banknotes.
By the way,
are they really yours?
Of course.
The salary from your office
isn't that high, is it?
Long Dan collects it every month.
Do you not know how much
you earn every month?
No.
Are 1,000 taels not enough?
I can give you more.
No, no. It's enough.
You're much richer
than I thought.
Money isn't important.
Only the rich
can say so.
I'm not that rich.
Anyway, I can't take your banknotes.
Take them back.
I don't need money at all.
You need it now,
so take it.
Don't be shy.
- I...
- Miss, are you done?
Someone is coming!
Oh, I see.
It's my problem.
I'll take care of it.
Here are your banknotes.
You...
Thank you, Mr. Yu.
Hold on. Wait!
I'll invest
the money in your shop.
Give me a cut at the end of the year.
Didn't you say
money should be used to make money?
If I left these banknotes in a cupboard,
they might be chipped away
by worms or rats.
Alright. Fine.
I'll take 500 taels.
Thanks for your help.
Don't turn around.
Do not move.
How useless!
(Friends Gather Together)
She came out.
You should've used that matter
against Jiang Si.
But what happened?
She used it against you!
It was my fault.
I didn't recognize
that she was Jiang Si.
Idiot!
Cousin,
is she the best one
you chose to take revenge for me?
She was a member of the Linglong Troupe.
I thought she was smart
and good with words.
I didn't know she'd be so useless.
Get lost!
Get out of Her Grace's sight!
- Yes.
- Wait.
Did I allow you to leave?
If you're so bad with words,
don't bother
to speak ever again.
Drag her out
and silence her.
Guards!
Spare me, Your Grace!
Your Grace!
Young Master!
Help me, Young Master!
Young Master! Please!
Do you want to help her?
Of course not.
I can't care less about a performer.
Very well.
It's better to have her muted
when she doesn't know what to say
or say what she shouldn't have.
Trust me, Your Grace.
I won't say a word about this matter
to Uncle.
You're my cousin.
I certainly trust you.
But
look at the people
you found:
a stupid performer
and a useless scholar.
Ji Chongyi,
your father is a duke.
He might not be powerful,
but he holds a rank.
You're right, Your Grace.
You can hold others in awe.
I admire you for that.
I know Jiang Si all too well.
She's calculative
and thick-skinned.
She went to Capital Security
to cancel our engagement.
I bet
both Zhen Heng and Yu Qi
of that office are her lovers.
The two of them
are known to be tough.
It wouldn't be wise
to set her up
in the open.
That office again!
Do you think
I'm afraid of them?
You aren't, of course.
But we're right
under His Majesty's nose.
If we made too big a fuss,
and the General and Grand Princess found out,
it wouldn't be worth it.
It's hard to deal with Jiang Si,
but her brother, Jiang Zhan,
is a fool
and an easy target.
She cares about him
the most.
It'll be much easier to destroy her
by using him.
Bad news!
Bad news, Miss!
Young Master Zhan has gone missing again.
(Haitang Chamber)
Miss!
Master, Master!
Found him?
He isn't anywhere here.
Check the east courtyard.
Yes.
Master, he's not in the places
where he'd go fishing!
What about the tea house?
Go there and look!
Yes.
Si,
calm down, will you?
He used to hang out
every few days.
Don't worry too much.
He'll come back when he's tired.
Father, this time is different.
He'll be in danger!
He's an adult.
What could've happened?
Trust me. Things have changed.
It's you who have changed.
In the last few days,
you had him grounded,
making him learn martial arts
and read books.
I was surprised
that he didn't run out
until today.
Miss Si, Master.
How did it go, Master Qin?
Found anything?
No. I checked every corner of this house.
I also checked the places
where he'd go for drinks, music, and cuju
as you said
but found nothing.
The riverside.
Go to the riverside!
Mr. Yu!
Mr. Zhen!
(Capital Security Office, Court)
Miss Si sent me to seek help.
Young Master Zhan is missing.
Please gather enough people
to help us find him.
How long
has he been missing?
It's been half a day since this morning.
He's an adult.
It's only been a few hours.
He's not missing yet.
Our office can't take it
as a missing person case.
But Miss Si said
he might die if we didn't find him in time.
Long Dan, let's go.
- Yes.
- Stop.
It's against the law.
If we had to find everyone
who went missing
for a few hours in town,
our system would be destroyed.
You're right. Let's go.
Did you find anything?
No.
What about you guys here?
- Nothing.
- Anything there?
No.
What about you, Master Qin?
Negative.
Over here.
This way, please.
This is the best room
we have.
You won't get
a better view anywhere else in town.
Do you need a girl
to play music or sing songs?
Also, she can drink with you.
You'll have fun.
I don't need anyone
to play music or sing.
Leave me alone.
Sure. No problem.
Thanks.
Enjoy yourself.
Sure.
Again!
Come on.
Knock him down.
- Get him!
- Another round!
- How manly!
- Good.
Get him!
Pin him down!
Zhan!
- Si...
- Why are you here?
Master Qin...
We looked everywhere for you.
I... I was watching
Imperial Insignia Guards wrestling.
Go home with me.
Stop running around, Zhan.
Sure. I...
Hey, Yu!
You came, too.
Help me, please.
Si is crazy.
She imprisoned me. Come on!
Mr. Yu, thanks for your help today.
I'll escort you two back.
No need.
I'll bring him back.
Good day.
Let's go home. Come on!
Come to have dinner with us someday.
Good day, Mr. Yu.
Mr. Yu, thanks to you,
we found Miss Si's brother.
She made
desserts for you and had me
bring them over.
No wonder they look familiar.
We're friends.
No need to thank me.
Speaking of her,
she kind of
overreacted
earlier today.
Just to be sure,
was everything alright at the Jiang's,
or was there anything wrong with her brother?
All seemed well
except that there was something strange.
What was it?
Young Master Zhan said
Miss Si had never been strict with him.
But recently,
she became a different person.
She made him learn martial arts at home
and had a physician
come to take his pulse every day.
Young Master Zhan
kept complaining about it.
Earlier today,
he managed to sneak out.
We looked everywhere for him.
At first,
I thought she was anxious
because the Imperial Insignia Guard selection
was in a few days.
She wanted him to get ready at home.
When I helped her look for him earlier,
I noticed
that she had replaced
all the servants in his courtyard.
She'd test
everything he ate every day
with a silver needle.
I think she was paranoid
just like she was today.
He only hung out for a few hours,
but she went crazy.
Was it that bad?
Is there someone trying to
harm Jiang Zhan?
He might be an earl's son,
but he can't inherit the rank.
Who'd waste their time harming him?
You're wrong.
Miss Si
has always been cautious.
She must've acted like this for a reason.
Master Qin, you know,
I'm also a martial artist.
I'll go with you tomorrow.
If Miss Si
still has concerns,
she can come along, too.
That'd be great.
I'll relay your message to her.
- Cheers.
Cheers.
(Zhou)
I'm off duty today.
Jiang Zhan can't stay indoors all the time.
It's bad for his mood and health.
I'll teach him.
Master Qin is here with us as well.
No need to worry, Miss Si.
I appreciate your help, Mr. Yu.
I'll leave you guys alone, Zhan.
You're really good!
You volunteered to teach me
to ride and shoot to help me out.
Thanks, man.
You're welcome, man.
Well then,
keep a squatting stance for one hour first
to warm up.
Sure. One hour...
Wait.
Look at me.
I'm warmed up.
I don't need to squat.
I can begin shooting now.
Let's shoot.
When you sneaked out yesterday,
your family was worried sick.
Are you trying to escape punishment?
You should be on my side.
You're my man.
Fine. As your man,
I have to
be responsible for you.
I'll have Miss Si watch you.
No, wait!
I'm squatting. Look.
- Calm down. Don't be mad.
- You...
That was for your sister.
Mr. Zhen.
Are you bringing Miss Si flowers again?
I think she and Young Master Zhan
went to the turf in the western suburbs.
Thanks.
My Lady,
just now, Mr. Zhen
came to bring Miss Si flowers again.
What did he bring this time?
Gardenias.
Last time, it was Lan-tsao.
Just now, he brought gardenias.
How sweet.
Si is
such a lucky girl.
(Zhou)
♪ Looking back, I recall our first encounter ♪
Great marksmanship!
Excellent!
You shoot with great precision.
Teach me now!
♪ I can't make up my mind ♪
♪ Can I still make it through the long night ♪
♪ I fear that we'll part again ♪
♪ A piercing ache lingers within ♪
♪ Shattering the dreams ♪
Miss,
do you adore Mr. Yu so much
that you can't take your eyes off him?
What are you talking about, Aman?
Your eyes are fixated on him.
No.
♪ I can't forget about you ♪
♪ However long the road is ♪
Great! Brilliant!
It hasn't been an hour. Squat.
Chest out.
Chin up, chest out, and breeze.
Mr. Zhen.
You're practicing hard, Young Master Zhan.
It's nothing at all.
Mr. Zhen.
Miss Si.
Miss,
I'm going to boil some water.
The gardenias are beautiful.
A friend of mine,
who was into gardening,
planted them.
Such flowers smell nice.
They're simple and pleasant.
I think they're perfect for you.
Thank you,
but I can't take them.
Hold it.
Don't feel pressured.
They're nothing expensive.
It's not about money.
You see,
you're a gentleman.
You're pure and unworldly.
However,
I'm not as good as you think.
I don't deserve your appreciation.
You should
be with a better girl.
Did I do anything wrong
that annoyed you?
Tell me. I'll change.
No, Zhen.
You're a good man.
It's my fault.
I disappoint
Mrs. Zhen and you.
Miss Si,
don't worry.
I won't force you to do anything.
I'll explain it to my mother.
Once you accept me,
I'll propose to you.
As for the flowers,
I'll bring them back
and tend them well.
If one day, you'd like to keep them,
I'll bring them over again.
Good day.
Mr. Yu.
(The End of Episode 12)
♪ From place to place ♪
♪ I drift in the world alone ♪
♪ The cool breeze comes and goes ♪
♪ I dare to love and hate ♪
♪ Ask the day and the night ♪
♪ If they saw a glimmer fall and take root ♪
♪ Growing between us ♪
♪ And breeding love ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ In the end, we're still together ♪
♪ Like shadows ♪
♪ We're brave enough to advance together ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ And stars ♪
♪ Don't ask what our fate is ♪
♪ Let life carve the growth rings ♪
♪ We'll reach the end eventually ♪
♪ All will bloom in spring ♪
♪ We promise each other the future ♪
♪ Our bond trickles down from youth ♪
♪ Time glows ♪
♪ Together, we'll see light ♪
♪ Smile at each other for the future ♪
♪ We travel at night in the cold ♪
♪ The moonlight shines like water ♪
♪ Those in love will have sweet dreams ♪
♪ Cherish each other in the future ♪
♪ Time goes by, but memories remain ♪
♪ Take a look to remember everything ♪
♪ We will see flowers fill the city again ♪